FESTUS BENJAMIN

festusbenjamin02@gmail.com | +255763104775

Summary

A young motivated, adaptable and responsible full stack developer ready to utilize the technical skills developed through past work experience in this field. Sensitive to employee concerns, I have a proven aptitude, methodical and customer-focused approach to work and a strong drive to see things through to completion.

Skills

- Software development
- Typescript/JavaScript
- React.js
- Php/Yii2
- NodeJS
- REST API's
- SQL
- Version control(git)
- Graphics design
- Microsoft office skills
- Software troubleshooting skills (Linux & Windows)
- Adaptability and flexibility
- Time management and problem solving
- Effective communication and Analytical skills

Projects

- **1.** My Portfolio
- **2.** E-commerce Web App
- 3. Social media web App
- 4. School Management System
- **5.** Office Management System

Experience

January 2022 - Present

Eastern Africa Statistical Training Center Title: **System Developer**

Key Responsibilities

• Designing and developing systems.

June 2021 – December 2021 Merroe Limited Title: IT Officer

Key Responsibilities

- Designing, Implementing and maintenance of the company's E-commerce website.
- Hosting and troubleshooting problems from the server.
- Digital marketing.

July 2019 – September 2019 Jointasoft Company

Title: Web and Graphics designer

Key Responsibilities

- Designing websites before implementing by creating mock ups.
- Designing Logos, Fliers, Brochures, Posters and Business cards.

July 2018 – September 2018 Tanzania Education Research Network (TERNET) Title: Software Developer

Key Responsibility

• Customizing Open Source Software (mainly DSPACE) according to the need of a certain organization.

Education & Qualifications

School/College	Year of passing	Degree/Certification
University of Dar es Salaam	2017 - 2020	Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (BSc. In CS)
Baobab Secondary School	2015 - 2017	Advanced Certificate of Secondary Education (ACSEE)
Eagles Secondary School	2011 - 2014	Certificate of Secondary Education (CSEE)
Filbert Bayi primary school	2004 - 2010	Primary School Leaving Examination (PSLE)

References

Mr. Lucas J. Nsinde

Software developer

Tanzania Education Research

Network (TERNET)

Location: Dar-es-Salaam,

Tanzania

Tel: +255758110359

Email: <u>ipalilolucas6@gmail.com</u>

Mr. Emmanuel Damas

Lecturer

University of Dar es Salaam (UDSM) **Location:** Dar-es-Salaam, Tanzania

Tel: +255713337777

Email: edamas83@gmail.com

Mr. Kelvin Rweshobora

Lecturer & Head of ICT Dept. Eastern Africa Statistical Training

Center (EASTC)

Location: Dar-es-Salaam, Tanzania

Tel: +255714267020

Email:kelvinrweshobora@gmail.com